<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>atelier ah</title>
    <link>https://atelierah.com</link>
    <description>simple horizontal totality through which all this goes</description>
    <language>ko</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 07:25:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://atelierah.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <image>
      <url>https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/favicon.png</url>
      <title>atelier ah</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com</link>
    </image>

    <item>
      <title>norrri cafe</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com/press/1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://atelierah.com/press/1</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:27:28 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>brique magazine</description>
      <media:content url="https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/press_06.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ATELIER AH</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com/works/6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://atelierah.com/works/6</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:26:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>We perceive &quot;white&quot; as the state of nothingness, emptiness, a vessel that can be filled, and a symbol of purity.
The landscape of white becomes a background that embraces all shades of color, while at the same time evoking a peculiar sense of unfamiliarity when faced with its luminous presence.
White is not merely a color. It is a texture that recalls materiality, a spatial and temporal void that contains its own depth and rhythm.

Sostel is a communication company that operates underground relay systems and broadband radio networks, connecting domestic and international signals.
The first impression we had of the client was one of clarity and progressive vision.
Their new 600-pyeong (2,000 m²) headquarters was envisioned not simply as a place for research and work, but as an open ground where people and the company could share time and interact.

How can a space allow people of different characters to harmonize together?
The workplace, in many ways, becomes a place where one spends more time than at home.
It therefore becomes an extension of the self.
Into this space, we sought to infuse white.
The strangeness that emerges from white is not momentary—it unfolds over time, like a canvas of emotions, never still but constantly reshaped by new landscapes.
It opens the possibility of imagination simply through being seen.
When we look at a blank sheet of paper, we rarely say &quot;it&apos;s white,&quot; but rather, we feel its emptiness.
By giving the space the presence of white—of no color—we erase the dominance of walls, furniture, and objects, and instead focus on the ever-changing hues that people themselves bring.
We share and fill the blankness between ourselves, quietly gathering to form a subtle sense of order.

The same philosophy extends to the building&apos;s façade.
The client wanted the headquarters to stand out from its surroundings.
We clad a steel frame structure with a white curtain wall.
While this choice was partly driven by budget constraints, it was also an intentional expression of structural purity—an elegance distilled to its essence.
The rhythmic vertical curtain wall captures light and creates depth across the façade, revealing diverse expressions through the changing seasons.
It becomes not just an exterior skin, but a device that draws time and nature into the building.
When visiting the site, we were surrounded by a context of vivid colors and monotonous windows.
Amid it all, what caught our eye was a single sheet of white paper lying on the concrete floor.
Despite its simplicity, it stood out more than any color or form around it.
Within the flow that accumulates layer by layer, not in a single moment, there lies a faint line that quietly opens up — carrying an intensity that makes the white even more distinct.

Inside, the design places people at the center while accommodating function.
The first floor houses laboratories and testing spaces; the second, the CEO&apos;s office, main workspace, and areas for partner companies; the third, a rooftop garden, gym, and private studios for rest and exchange.
Meeting rooms on each level serve as central places for gathering and communication.

Ceilings inevitably carry mechanical systems—HVAC, lighting, sprinklers.
Rather than letting these dominate, we sought to conceal and simplify them, allowing the focus to remain on human activity and expression.
Thus, we introduced louvers.
Each 200mm-deep louver creates a tactile rhythm, and the light diffusing along their lines recalls the residue of sunlight filtering through fabric.
Lighting fixtures were designed to disappear, leaving only the presence of light itself.
The floor is finished with long tiles that visually extend the space, enhancing openness.
Walls are defined by horizontal material divisions aligned to standard heights, primarily in shades of white—subtly varied so that depending on the light, the same surface reveals nuanced tonal boundaries.

White is not a color, but rather the absence of it.
It is paradoxical—colorless yet luminous—and its simplicity draws us into quiet contemplation.
I call this the purity of white: a freedom and naturalness that lead to a fundamental aesthetic.
Within this space of white, we hope that the Sostel headquarters becomes a place where people&apos;s time gathers and new landscapes continuously unfold.</description>
      <media:content url="https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/works/1769668134757-v8dw12.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>gilchi cafe</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com/works/1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://atelierah.com/works/1</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 03:18:18 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>In a rough city surrounded by loud noises, dark asphalt roads, and gray buildings. In our busy daily lives, we become empty and only the outline remains.
I&apos;m wandering around the city, lost. In the gap, I discovered a trunk of light that gave me a sense of warmth. I will unconsciously follow the trunk of light. 
The blur hidden in the darkness for me becomes more and more vivid and filled with warmth. 
Our inner images overlap, and our insides, where only the outline remains, become enriched.

When I met my client for the first time, I told him my story of how she was tired of everyday life and society and had lost direction. So she thought of creating a space for myself, like a haven, and decided to start with a cafe As She talk about my loss of direction,
 She laughed and was told that she usually has trouble finding her way even when looking at a map, I&apos;m bad with directions. Therefore, I wanted the cafe to be one that both people visiting the cafe and people like myself could easily visit and enjoy their own time here. Afterwards, as I was thinking about the direction of the project design, 
an image that came to mind appeared in books and movies: when you lose yourself or are in a hopeless situation, a ray of light falls and you follow that light and escape.
 I focused on the meaning of light.I started the project with the idea of how can we guide people who get lost through the penetration of light at the main entrance of the space?

The existing spatial layout consists of three sequences in the form of stairs. It connects to one space, but can give three different feels. Since the first floor consists of a piloti parking structure, Windows and doors do not allow sunlight to enter, except at state entrances. 
There is no difference between day and night; it is cold and dark, like a cave. Usually if it&apos;s dark, we try to dilute it with lighter tones, but the tone &amp; manner of the space was instead filled with cold grays and blacks. By installing light, we express and fill the space in the darkness.
 A strong light can feel overwhelming at first, but a single light in the darkness gives a sense of warmth and permeation between the overwhelming. Therefore, we filled the center wall of the interior plane with Barisol, allowing a single light to penetrate all the way to the façade Due to the strong backlighting in the first sequence, 
only the shapes of the furniture and the shapes of the people coming fill the space. When you pass in front of the backlighting, only the frame of the shape remains. It has the meaning of a person who has lost his sense of self in everyday life and society. 
From the second sequence, it is filled with a faint light. While calming the atmosphere of intense light, you can return your darkened self to its original color. In the third sequence you will face a counter. Visitors will linger on black wood furniture under subdued light. 
We used ink stick to create a deep black finish for the furniture. Then, through the varnish coating, I applied the color of light in the darkness. Only the light and myself exist in the dim light I hope it will be your own space where you can look at the light and find comfort for your tired self. 

The cafe name was created by the client. I wanted a cafe that anyone could easily visit, even people who were just as disoriented as I was. &apos;GILCHI&apos; means &apos;one who has lost direction&apos; in Korean.</description>
      <media:content url="https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/01_gilchi_01.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>norrri ade cafe</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com/works/2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://atelierah.com/works/2</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 03:18:13 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>An alley in Uncheon-dong, Cheongju, filled with quiet small houses,
 Children gathered at the playground in every alley. It was a place where you could talk, run around with friends, and do what you wanted. 
All the scenery we could see looked round. It was a free and dynamic space, but when we remembered that time, we felt completely at ease.  
When I first met the client and entered the space, There was an unknown partition installed that made it impossible to guess whether it was a dining hall in the past. 
The traces surrounded by mold gave the impression that it had been there for many years. The client said they wanted it to be a warm space where everyone felt comfortable, along with vibrant and colorfully colored drinks. 
While listening to the story, I could see a playground where children were playing outside the curved window. At that time, some of the old memories that came to me during my busy daily life were of warmth. 
I started this project by recalling memories of playing at the playground as a child and how ordinary daily life became filled with various colors and emotions.

The space is part of the playground outside the window, and we thought it was important to create harmony as an extension of it. 
We tried to imbue the space with the impression of primary color tones and free shapes that characterize the playground. However, we felt that including only a fully vibrant play area design was lacking in providing the sense of comfort and coziness that our clients were looking for. 
Therefore, we hope that the colorful ade will become an element of the space under the overall well-organized tone and warm atmosphere. The primary-colored furniture and the scenery outside the window become the center of the space, and the curved facade of the existing building naturally connects with the interior, creating a dynamic sense of life as the surface of the interior space rolls as if children are playing. 
I wanted the design to coexist in two directions: dynamism and comfort.

As you enter the entrance, the diagonal counter is intended to utilize the space, but is arranged as if to play a prank on customers entering the space.  
The diagonal curved shape allows natural light coming through the window to flow through the curve, giving a strong warmth, while also raising questions about the space behind it, visible through the gap. 
The interior floor was designed in a dynamic form, imagining the feel of a park walkway, and harmonized with the burgundy brick exterior of the existing building. Brick tiles and epoxy gravel materials were chosen to add warmth and connection between the interior and exterior. The warm white color makes the curved shape and light stand out more. 
It will harmonize with the primary colored furniture and dynamic flooring. Afterwards, I hope to be able to look out the window and see the disappearing border between the inside and the playground outside the window.

To put it simply, a playground is a play of colors and a feast of shapes. Although it looks like a combination of complex shapes and colors, I simplified it with lines and understated tones throughout the study. 
The branding logo evokes the afterimage of &quot;nori&quot; (the Korean word for play is pronounced as &quot;nori&quot; when pronounced verbally), which is pronounced like a baby cooing, and the &quot;o&quot; rolls down, and embodies the &quot;norrri&quot; logo.</description>
      <media:content url="https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/02_norrri_02.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>all&apos;s lounge pub</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com/works/3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://atelierah.com/works/3</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 03:18:07 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>People say that they &quot;share a drink&quot; when they drink together.
A glass is a vessel that holds alcohol, yet its shape, size, and material differ depending on the type of drink, the era, and the person who holds it.
According to the accompanying food, it can feel rustic or refined.
Just as the outcome of a painting changes with the artist&apos;s materials, so too are drinking and painting alike in spirit.

The first glass one shares and the glass shared after many nights together hold different drinks, people, and stories.
Yet within all those moments lies the same sense of ease and freedom.
As colors fill a canvas, the space where drinks are shared becomes a painting in itself.

Just as every person has their own taste and people they feel at ease with, there is a joy in finding tools that suit oneself.
And when you share time with those whose tastes align, a quiet comfort arises.
An empty glass is filled, and the colors of each person blend into a single meaning.

When I first met the client, they wanted to create a bar where people could communicate freely and comfortably.
Whether owner or guest, anyone should feel welcome—a place for open connection.
Thus, the name Alls was born, meaning &quot;a bar where anyone can come and share time together.&quot;

While conceiving the design, I saw communication reflected in the idea of a &quot;studio.&quot;
Just as various drinks—whiskey, wine, beer—mix to create new flavors,
different brushes and pigments give birth to diverse styles in painting.
The bar, I thought, could be like an artist&apos;s studio—
a space where unique elements coexist and create new expressions.

I wanted to translate the meaning of &quot;sharing a drink&quot; into the idea of
&quot;a single canvas that embraces countless colors.&quot;
Imagining a canvas-like space, I recalled the scene of an artist&apos;s studio—
easels and canvases, brushes and paints,
and traces of color splattered on the floor during the creative process.

Those traces reminded me of shattered tempered glass.
When struck at the edge, tempered glass breaks into small square fragments,
resembling paint splatters scattered across the ground.
Bronze, blue, and green glass pieces were mixed with pebble-finish flooring,
adding vibrant tones to the floor, while epoxy coating softened the rough texture.

The walls were left bare, like a blank canvas—
a surface waiting to be filled with encounters between people and objects.
As glasses are exchanged, the space itself becomes a living painting.
On the ceiling, colorful glass vessels are arranged beneath the light,
so that when illuminated, it evokes the moment when a brush, soaked in watercolor, touches the canvas.

In this space where countless colors blend into one canvas,
the act of sharing a drink becomes a form of art,
and the space itself becomes a gesture of connection.</description>
      <media:content url="https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/03_pub_01.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>geumchon gukbap</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com/works/4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://atelierah.com/works/4</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 03:18:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>Before you even begin a day, it feels long. After one day has passed, the day seems short. In the midst of our fast-paced and busy daily lives, there is one dish that is indispensable. It is Korean soup. We are called Gukbab.
Gukbab can be likened to a short break. For those who are weary of life, a short, deep rest means more than a meal. It is called Korean fast food because it is a food that can satisfy hunger in a short time.

The client is an authentic Gukbab restaurant with 20 years of experience that has become famous for its unique pig head recipe that has been developed over the years.
The food served here is so deep and delicious that other areas would visit in person just to have a bowl of soup. The client is a mother in her 70s who started a soup restaurant to raise her three siblings.
Now, she wanted to proceed with the restaurant expansion so she could run it with his family. When viewed in the context of my mother&apos;s life as a whole, this space is companion and beautiful years.

When I first started the project, I was more concerned with the meaning of Gukbab than the method of approaching the space. If you watch Korean movies, you will often see scenes where people eat with a bowl of soup in front of them.
And generally speaking, the love for soup is genuine. As people wiped the sweat from their brows, they seemed drawn to something and ate the Gukbab with all their might, without stopping to eat their spoons.
The highlight is when he grabs the heavy, rough bowl of soup with both hands and drinks it. Gukbab is a food that can be mixed with any ingredient in the rough container.

Various ingredients are put into a large cauldron and simmered until they are fused together into a single dish.
The process of making it accumulates the depth of time and the delicacies familiar to people, and even with just one bowl of soup, the pursuit of perfection continues.
It must be simple yet have depth, it must be flashy yet plain. Although it is a new space, I wanted to see traces of my mother&apos;s years permeating the space.

Earthenware bowls have been used as traditional Korean bowls for many years. The clay-fired ware is rough, but even after many years, it still retains a simplicity and elegance. Unchanging vessels give a familiar feeling.
The unique characteristics of the Earthenware Bowl highlight the flavor and essence of the contents. I struggled with how to express the feel of the Earthenware bowl in my mind in the space.

We used terracotta to create a harmonious look while making the most of the traces of the existing space, creating the feel of earthen walls.
The point walls consisted of panels made of lacquer paper. Lacquer paper is a traditional Korean paper, and the lacquer paper is made by applying lacquer to the paper using sap obtained by cutting into the lacquer tree.
The process of making can be simple. The process of applying lacquer to the paper and letting it dry was repeated four or five times. This process results in different colors in the paper and different patterns or depths in the material.
Each piece of lacquer paper becomes a work of art. We selected 70 of them. We created patterns and created a plain yet colorful and natural wall. 

As I said earlier, Gukbap is a Korean fast food.
As soon as you enter the restaurant, the clarity of just having to shout out the number of dishes you want, the speed at which the food comes out as soon as you order, 
and the simplicity of being able to eat it with just a spoon all speak to the importance of the harmony between the kitchen and the dining area within the space.
The kitchen layout is broadly divided into three sections: a space for aging the main pig&apos;s head, a space for cooking the aged meat, and a space for finishing preparations before guests serve.
As there is a trend for dining in halls to be more for single-person consumption, clent wanted a hall layout that could accommodate single, double, four, or even six-person seating.
Because the overall space is small, the tables are spaced closely together. At each table border, we placed an auxiliary table to act as a partition, where sauces and accessories necessary for guests can be placed.
The space appears to have many complexly divided boundaries, but by minimizing the number of walls and resolving the issue with furniture, we wanted it to look like one big space when viewed from the outside.
It would be great if the space could become a place where the breath of the visitors and the breath of the restaurant owner harmonize and become one breath.
The space may have seemed cramped due to the large number of people and the way meals are served, but the existing gabled structure of the building has been utilized to create a sense of openness vertically.
Then, a straw mat structure was installed on the existing ceiling. One of the characteristics of Earthenware bowls is that they have tiny holes because they are made from earth, so the bowl has a breathing effect that allows air to circulate well.
I was inspired and wanted to express that breathing feeling through lighting and the light filtering through the small holes in the straw mat. We hope that the ceiling will create a comfortable atmosphere and open air for those staying there.

South Korea&apos;s rapid change is both an advantage and a disadvantage. In a busy society,
When you enter this space in the midst of a busy society, we hope you will find solace in the remnants of Korea&apos;s past, take a short break, and feel the feast of richness that is ripened together as one.</description>
      <media:content url="https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/04_geumchon_03.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SORCETEL OFFICE</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com/works/5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://atelierah.com/works/5</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 03:17:42 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>We perceive &quot;white&quot; as the state of nothingness, emptiness, a vessel that can be filled, and a symbol of purity.
The landscape of white becomes a background that embraces all shades of color, while at the same time evoking a peculiar sense of unfamiliarity when faced with its luminous presence.
White is not merely a color. It is a texture that recalls materiality, a spatial and temporal void that contains its own depth and rhythm.

Sostel is a communication company that operates underground relay systems and broadband radio networks, connecting domestic and international signals.
The first impression we had of the client was one of clarity and progressive vision.
Their new 600-pyeong (2,000 m²) headquarters was envisioned not simply as a place for research and work, but as an open ground where people and the company could share time and interact.

How can a space allow people of different characters to harmonize together?
The workplace, in many ways, becomes a place where one spends more time than at home.
It therefore becomes an extension of the self.
Into this space, we sought to infuse white.
The strangeness that emerges from white is not momentary—it unfolds over time, like a canvas of emotions, never still but constantly reshaped by new landscapes.
It opens the possibility of imagination simply through being seen.
When we look at a blank sheet of paper, we rarely say &quot;it&apos;s white,&quot; but rather, we feel its emptiness.
By giving the space the presence of white—of no color—we erase the dominance of walls, furniture, and objects, and instead focus on the ever-changing hues that people themselves bring.
We share and fill the blankness between ourselves, quietly gathering to form a subtle sense of order.

The same philosophy extends to the building&apos;s façade.
The client wanted the headquarters to stand out from its surroundings.
We clad a steel frame structure with a white curtain wall.
While this choice was partly driven by budget constraints, it was also an intentional expression of structural purity—an elegance distilled to its essence.
The rhythmic vertical curtain wall captures light and creates depth across the façade, revealing diverse expressions through the changing seasons.
It becomes not just an exterior skin, but a device that draws time and nature into the building.
When visiting the site, we were surrounded by a context of vivid colors and monotonous windows.
Amid it all, what caught our eye was a single sheet of white paper lying on the concrete floor.
Despite its simplicity, it stood out more than any color or form around it.
Within the flow that accumulates layer by layer, not in a single moment, there lies a faint line that quietly opens up — carrying an intensity that makes the white even more distinct.

Inside, the design places people at the center while accommodating function.
The first floor houses laboratories and testing spaces; the second, the CEO&apos;s office, main workspace, and areas for partner companies; the third, a rooftop garden, gym, and private studios for rest and exchange.
Meeting rooms on each level serve as central places for gathering and communication.

Ceilings inevitably carry mechanical systems—HVAC, lighting, sprinklers.
Rather than letting these dominate, we sought to conceal and simplify them, allowing the focus to remain on human activity and expression.
Thus, we introduced louvers.
Each 200mm-deep louver creates a tactile rhythm, and the light diffusing along their lines recalls the residue of sunlight filtering through fabric.
Lighting fixtures were designed to disappear, leaving only the presence of light itself.
The floor is finished with long tiles that visually extend the space, enhancing openness.
Walls are defined by horizontal material divisions aligned to standard heights, primarily in shades of white—subtly varied so that depending on the light, the same surface reveals nuanced tonal boundaries.

White is not a color, but rather the absence of it.
It is paradoxical—colorless yet luminous—and its simplicity draws us into quiet contemplation.
I call this the purity of white: a freedom and naturalness that lead to a fundamental aesthetic.
Within this space of white, we hope that the Sostel headquarters becomes a place where people&apos;s time gathers and new landscapes continuously unfold.</description>
      <media:content url="https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/05_sorcetel_01.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>geumchon gukbap</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com/press/7</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://atelierah.com/press/7</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 02:07:40 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>yinjispace magazine</description>
      <media:content url="https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/press_01.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>norrri cafe</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com/press/2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://atelierah.com/press/2</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:58:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <description></description>
      <media:content url="https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/press_05.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>norrri cafe</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com/press/3</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://atelierah.com/press/3</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:58:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <description></description>
      <media:content url="https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/press_07.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>norrri cafe</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com/press/4</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://atelierah.com/press/4</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:58:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <description></description>
      <media:content url="https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/press_04.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>gilchi cafe</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com/press/5</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://atelierah.com/press/5</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:58:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <description></description>
      <media:content url="https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/press_03.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>geumchon gukbap</title>
      <link>https://atelierah.com/press/6</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://atelierah.com/press/6</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:58:22 GMT</pubDate>
      <description></description>
      <media:content url="https://pub-4b716c374bc747948e9ac588042939de.r2.dev/press_02.jpg" medium="image"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
